所以我们之前讲过伪类。
So we talked about pseudo classes before.
所以现在让我们来谈谈伪元素，
So now let's talk about pseudo elements,
这是一个不错的小 CSS 功能
which are a nice little CSS feature
这是值得学习的。
that is worth learning about.
所以伪元素本质上是元素
So pseudo elements are essentially elements
HTML中不存在的，
that don't exist in the HTML,
但是我们仍然可以在 CSS 中选择和设置样式。
but that we can still select and style in CSS.
还有一些常见的例子
And some common examples of that
是段落的第一个字母
are the first letter of a paragraph
或段落的第一行
or the first line of a paragraph
或者当然是其他一些文本。
or of some other texts of course.
所以让我们从我给你的第一个例子开始，
So let's start with that first example that I gave you,
的第一个字母。
of the first letter.
那么我们可以使用首字母伪元素做什么
So what we can do using a first letter pseudo element
就是在这里选择这个H1的第一个字母，
is to select the very first letter of this H1 here,
这将是这个表情符号，
which would be this emoji,
然后我们可以以不同的方式格式化它。
and then we could format it differently.
就这样，
And so with that,
我们可以修正这也是斜体的事实，
we could fix the fact that this is also italic,
这没有多大意义。
which doesn't make a lot of sense.
所以最后，它会看起来像这样。
So in the end, it's going to look like this.
所以不再是斜体，
So no longer italic,
甚至在右侧有一些空间。
and even with some space there on the right side.
所以让我们看看它是如何工作的。
So let's see how that is going to work.
所以让我们来到这里的某个地方，
So let's come somewhere down here,
然后让我们说H1，
and then let's say H1,
所以我们选择H1，
so we are selecting H1,
然后使用两个冒号写入伪元素。
and then the pseudo element is written using two colons.
所以冒号冒号，然后是第一个字母。
So colon colon, and then first letter.
好的。
All right.
所以伪类只用一个冒号编写
So pseudo classes are written with just one colon
并且伪元素带有两个冒号。
and the pseudo elements are with two colons.
因此，我们可以很容易地区分
And so with that, we can easily distinguish
伪元素和伪类之间。
between pseudo elements and pseudo classes.
因此，让我们为第一个字母设置样式。
So let's style that very first letter.
假设字体样式不应该是斜体，而是正常的。
Let's say font style should be not italic, but normal.
让我们也给它一些右边的空白，
And let's also give it some margin to the right,
五个像素。
of five pixels.
你去吧。
And there you go.
你看到了吗？
Do you see that?
现在有一些空间，文本不再是斜体。
Now there is some space and the text is no longer italic.
伟大的。
Great.
而且当然，
And of course,
这也适用于任何其他标题外，
that would also have worked with any other off the headings,
以及任何其他字母。
and with any other letter.
所以当然它不仅仅适用于表情符号。
So of course it doesn't just work with emojis.
假设我们想要 H2 的第一个字母，
So let's say we wanted the first letter here of the H2,
要大很多。
to be a lot bigger.
例如，假设字体大小为 60 像素，
Let's say font size 60 pixels for example,
或使其更加明显 80 像素。
or to make it even more visible 80 pixels.
你去吧。
And there you go.
所以基本上我们选择了这个伪元素，
So basically we selected this pseudo element,
这实际上也不是 HTML 中的元素，
which again is not actually an element in the HTML,
但它好像是一个我们可以选择的元素，
but it as if it was an element that we can select,
然后在此处进行样式设置。
and then style right here.
好的。
Okay.
但是这里的这个并不那么有趣。
But this one here is not that interesting.
所以让我们删除它，让我们尝试另一个，
So let's remove it and let's try another one,
这是第一线。
which is first-line.
例如，让我们尝试选择所有段落，
For example, let's try to select all the paragraphs,
然后在那里，选择第一行并设置样式。
and then in there, select and style the very first line.
假设我们实际上想把颜色染成红色，
And let's say we actually wanted to color to be red,
只是作为一个演示。
just as a demo.
所以你会看到它实际上工作得很好。
And so you'll see that actually worked just fine.
所以这是一个段落，它是第一行。
So this is a paragraph and it is the first line.
所以是红色的。
So it's red.
这里也是。
The same here.
这里、这里、这里和到处都是一样的。
The same here and here and here and really everywhere.
对？
Right?
现在让我向您展示另一个新的选择器
Now let me actually show you another new selector
你所做的还不知道，
that you don't know yet,
这是相邻元素选择器
which is the adjacent element selector
或相邻的兄弟选择器。
or the adjacent sibling selector.
所以兄弟元素基本上是一个元素
So a sibling element is basically an element
那是同一个父母的一部分。
that is part of the same parent.
例如，在这里，
So for example, here,
这个 P 是这个 P 和这个 P 的兄弟
this P is a sibling of this one and of this one
这个和所有其他的，
and of this one and all these other ones,
因为它们都在同一个容器内，
because they are all inside of the same container,
在这种情况下，就是这篇文章。
which is in this case, this article.
对。
Right.
现在，相邻的兄弟姐妹是兄弟姐妹
Now, the adjacent sibling is a sibling
这实际上是下一个元素。
that is actually the very next element.
例如，
So for example,
这个 H3 的相邻兄弟是这里的这一段。
the adjacent sibling of this H3 is this paragraph here.
好的。
Okay.
所以基本上相邻的元素
So basically the adjacent element
是紧随其后的兄弟姐妹。
is the sibling that comes right after it.
实际上有一个选择器。
And there's actually a selector for that.
所以我想做的是只选择段落
So what I want to do is to only select the paragraphs
在 H3 之后。
that come after the H3s.
所以这将是这个和这个。
So that's going to be this one and this one.
好的。
Okay.
所以让我们说H3然后加上。
So let's say H3 and then plus.
所以这里的加号是相邻的兄弟选择器。
So the plus here is the adjacent sibling selector.
因此，如果我们现在保存它，那么您实际上会看到，
So if we save that now, then you'll see that in fact,
仅在 H3 之后的段落，
only the paragraphs that are immediately after the H3,
所以这个和这个，都被选中了。
so this one and this one, have been selected.
然后在那里，当然，
And then in there, of course,
实际上只有第一行被选中并设置了样式。
only the first line has actually been selected and styled.
好的。
Okay.
但这实际上让我们失望了。
But that's actually turned us off.
用处不大，
It's not that helpful,
但我还是想给你参考
but I still want to give you the reference
一线的这里
here of first-line
也许更重要的是，
and maybe even more importantly,
相邻兄弟选择器的，
of the adjacent sibling selector,
在某些情况下，这实际上非常重要。
which in some cases is actually quite important.
好的。
All right.
但现在让我们实际使用可能最常用的
But now let's actually use the probably most used
和最重要的伪元素，
and most important pseudo element,
分别是 after 和 before 伪元素。
which are the after and the before pseudo elements.
所以 after 伪元素创建了一个伪元素，
So the after pseudo element creates a pseudo element,
那将自动成为第一个孩子
that will automatically be the very first child
的选定元素。
of the selected element.
我敢肯定这听起来很奇怪，
And I'm sure that that sounds quite strange,
但这实际上非常有用
but this can actually be very useful
对于一些小的化妆品风格
for some small cosmetic style
我们不想为其添加新元素
for which we don't want to necessarily add a new element
到 HTML。
to the HTML.
所以让我告诉你我的意思。
So let me show you what I mean by that.
而且，在演示中向您展示是最容易的。
And, it's easiest to show you in the demo.
所以我说的是这个黄色的小东西。
So what I'm talking about is this yellow, small thing here.
让我们给我们更多的空间，以便我们可以实际看到它。
Let's give us some more space so we can actually see it.
所以本质上我在这里添加了这个小的化妆品风格。
So essentially I'm adding this small cosmetic style here.
所以简单地说这是一篇顶级文章。
So simply saying that this is a top article.
好的。
All right.
所以对于这个非常小的，
And so for this very small,
说点事，
let's say thing,
我们不需要在 HTML 中添加一个全新的元素。
we don't need to add a whole new element into our HTML.
我的意思是，我们当然可以这样做，
I mean, of course we could do that,
但这是一个很好的用例
but this is a good use case
向您展示之前或之后的伪元素。
to show you the before or the after a pseudo elements.
好的。
All right.
让我们把它放回去，回到这里。
Let's put it back and go back here.
所以，是的，
And so, yeah,
所以请记住这里的这个元素，
so remember that this element here,
这里接近这个H1。
is close to this a H1 here.
所以我们要做什么
And so what we will do
是创建伪元素之后，
is to create the after a pseudo element,
基本上在H1之后。
basically after the H1.
所以，我只会写代码
So, I will just write the code
然后它会更容易理解。
and then it will be a bit easier to understand.
所以冒号冒号，然后是冒号。
So colon colon, and then after.
现在是第一个属性
And now the first property
此处必须指定的是 content 属性。
that is mandatory to specify here is the content property.
所以我们指定内容
So we specify content
然后在这里我们需要写一些东西。
and then here we need to write something.
它实际上可以只是一个空字符串。
And it can actually just be an empty string.
所以就像这样的空文本。
So just this empty text like this.
但在这种情况下，我们想要顶部。
But in this case we want top.
好的。
Okay.
但即使你不想要任何文本
But even if you don't want any texts
在你的伪元素中，
in your pseudo elements,
您仍然必须定义内容属性。
you still have to define the content property.
而实际上在这一点上，
And actually at this point,
伪元素应该已经在我们的页面中可见。
the pseudo elements should already be visible in our page.
所以让我们试一试。
So let's give it a try.
它看起来还没有。
And it looks like it's not there yet.
但是让我们在这里弄清楚。
But let's figure out right here.
哦，实际上它就在这里。
Oh, and actually it is here.
您会看到它在 H1 中。
You see that it's here in the H1.
所以我们实际上希望它在 H2 中。
So we want it in the H2 actually.
它就在那里。
And there it is.
所以有我们刚刚创建的这个元素
So there is this element that we just created
我们会稍微设计一下
and we will style it in a little bit
因为像这样，没有多大意义。
because like this, it doesn't make a lot of sense.
但在这里你实际上可以看到它，
But here you can actually see it,
即使在开发工具中，
even in the dev tools,
当你悬停它时，它就在那里。
and as you hover it, it is right there.
好的。
Okay.
但这不是更进一步的探针。
But that's no stylet a little bit further.
让我们给它一些背景颜色。
Let's give it some background color.
我将在此代码中使用一些漂亮的黄色。
I'm going to use some nice yellow with this code here.
F F E 七零 E.
F F E seven zero E.
好的。
All right.
所以现在这看起来更像是一个真实的元素。
And so now this looks more like a real element.
然后我们也可以改变字体大小，例如，
Then we can also change the font size, for example,
我们可以把它加粗。
we can make it bold.
那么让我们看看。
So let's see.
这看起来已经好一点了。
And that looks a little bit nicer already.
现在让我们给它一些填充。
And now let's give it some padding.
现在默认情况下，
Now by default,
任何伪元素实际上都是内联元素。
any pseudo element is actually an inline element.
所以如果我们想给它任何填充，
And so if we want to give it any padding,
我们希望盒子模型正常应用到它。
we want the box model to apply to it normally.
对？
Right?
所以为了做到这一点，
And so in order to do that,
我们需要将此元素渲染为内联块框。
we need to render this element as an inline block box.
所以显示，
So display,
内联块。
inline block.
所以这实际上是很好的用例之一
And so this is actually one of the great use cases
使用内联块。
of using inline block.
所以请注意这一点，也许。
And so take a note of that, maybe.
现在让我们在这里添加一些填充。
Now let's add some padding here.
假设顶部有五个像素
Let's say five pixels to the top
和十个像素的侧面。
and ten pixels to the sides.
好的。
Nice.
所以这看起来已经相当不错了。
So that's already looking quite good.
但现在我们需要添加最后一块拼图，
But now we need to add the final piece of the puzzle,
也就是把它放在一个有意义的地方。
which is to actually position it in a meaningful place.
所以请注意这里的元素是这样的，
So notice how right here, the element is like,
有点在元素的末尾。
kind of at the end of the element.
所以最后，一半的元素在它之外。
So at the end, and half of the element is outside of it.
所以在这里，在我们的例子中，
So while here, in our example,
让我们给，我们的H2，
let's give, our H2,
这里只是暂时的背景色，
just temporarily a background color here,
所以我们可以看到发生了什么。
so we can see what's happening.
所以背景颜色，
So background color,
橙。
orange.
好的。
Okay.
所以现在我们想要这个伪元素的位置，
And so now where we want this pseudo element to be located,
这里有点外面。
is here a bit outside.
所以首先让我们把它放在这个角落，
00:11:02,650 -->00:11:05,770
然后我们将把它移到外面。
So first let's put it here in this corner,
and then from that we will move it outside.
那么您认为我们如何才能实现这一目标？
So how do you think we can achieve that?
嗯，答案是绝对定位。
Well, the answer to that is absolute positioning.
好的。
All right.
所以我们需要做的第三件事
So the third thing that we need to do
为了绝对定位一个元素，
in order to absolutely position an element,
就是先给父元素，
is to first give the parent element,
我们想要的里面，
inside of which we want,
实际上是发生的定位，相对的位置。
actually the positioning to happen, the position relative.
还记得吗？
Remember that?
所以在这种情况下，
And so in this case,
那将是这个H2元素。
that's going to be this H2 element.
所以相对位置，
00:11:39,130​​ --> 00:11:42,203
现在我们已经准备好绝对定位这个元素了。
So position relative,
and now we are ready to absolutely position this element.
所以定位绝对。
So position absolute.
让我们把它放在顶部。
And let's put it at the top.
现在只是为了测试它，让我们放在左边。
And just to test it for now, let's put on the left.
所以这将是左上角。
So this will be the top left corner.
确实，效果很好。
And indeed that worked beautifully.
它就在这里。
It's right here.
只要注意发生了什么，
Just notice what happened,
如果我们关闭位置，相对于 H2，
if we turned off the position, relative here in the H2,
然后它会立即移动到这里，
then this would immediately move up here,
到页面的最顶部。
to the very top of the page.
对？
Right?
这就是为什么我们永远不能忘记相对定位
And so that's why we can never forget to position relative
在父元素上，
on the parent element,
我们希望在其中发生这种情况。
inside of which we want this to happen.
但现在我们希望它在右侧。
But now we want it here at the right side.
所以就在这里。
So right here.
现在让我们把它移出一点。
And now let's actually move it out a little bit.
所以向上移动并向右移动。
So move it up and move it to the right.
好的。
Okay.
而我这样做的原因，
And the reason why I'm doing that,
是为了让我给你看一些东西
is so that I can show you something
我们还没有谈到，
that we haven't also talked about yet,
这是负长度。
which is negative length.
所以如果我们在这里指定它，向右 25 像素，
So if we specify it here, 25 pixels to the right,
它会从右边移动，
it would move from the right,
这里基本上是向左这个方向。
here in this direction to the left, basically.
对？
Right?
所以从右边到这个方向有 25 个像素。
So 25 pixels from the right into this direction.
但是，如果我们设置一个负值，
However, if we set a negative value,
它会朝相反的方向移动。
it will move in the opposite direction.
所以现在它就在这里。
And so now it is right here.
所以在H1之外，至少部分
So outside of the H1 while, at least partially
对？
Right?
所以当然不是H1，而是H2。
So not the H1, but the H2, of course.
然后在顶部，让我们做同样的事情。
Then at the top, let's do the same.
假设是负 10 像素。
Let's say minus 10 pixels.
我猜它可能会更多。
And it could be even a bit more, I guess.
假设是负 15。
Let's say minus 15.
所以看起来好一点。
And so that looks a bit better.
好的。
Okay.
所以现在我们可以在这里真正摆脱这个了。
And so now we can get actually rid of this one here.
我们开始了。
And there we go.
所以看起来就像这个。
So that looks just like this one.
对？
Right?
嗯，有点不同。
Well, it's a bit different.
这个有点高，所以我们可以把它往下移。
This one is a bit more up, so we can move it back down.
比如说10。
Let's say 10.
而且颜色是黑色的。
And also the color is black.
所以让我们在这里做。
So let's do that here.
让我们保持一致并使用十六进制。
And let's stay consistent and use hexadecimal.
所以要让它变黑，
And so to make it black,
一直为零，零和零。
it's zero, zero and zero all the way.
现在让我们看看，这看起来完全一样。
And so now let's see, that that looks exactly the same.
但唯一的区别是它实际上是四、四、四。
But the only difference that it's actually four, four, four.
但这并不重要。
But that doesn't really matter.
再一次，
And once again,
我们刚刚创建和设置样式的这个元素，
this element that we just created and styled,
这里确实存在，
does exist here,
一种在 HTML 三
kind of in the HTML three
我们可以在 Def 工具中看到。
that we can see here in the Def tools.
但是当然在我们自己的 HTML 中，
But of course in our own HTML,
它在这里无处可寻，靠近这个 H2。
it is nowhere to be found here, close to this H2.
对。
Right.
所以 CSS，一旦我们在这里声明它，
So CSS, once we declare it here,
然后会自动创建它，
will then automatically create it,
我们会把它放在这里以便我们可以设置它的样式。
and we'll put it here so that we can style it.
所以当然是样式，然后出现在这里
So the styles of course, then appear down here
在样式面板中，
in the styles panel,
这是盒子模型的常用值。
and here are the usual values of the box model.
好的。
Okay.
这就是我们在 HTML 中使用伪元素的方式。
And so this is how we work with pseudo elements in HTML.
现在也有以前的。
Now there was also the before.
但实际上这看起来完全一样。
But actually that would look exactly the same way.
不同之处在于
The difference is that
after 基本上会成为最后一个子元素
after will basically become the very last child element
我们在这里选择的一个，
of the one that we are selecting here,
而在我们将成为第一个子元素之前。
while before we'll become the very first child element.
所以如果我们把这里改成以前，
So if we changed this here to before,
然后你会在这里看到，它切换了位置。
then you'll see that here, it switched position.
但是由于我们定位这个元素
But since we are positioning this element
以绝对的方式，
in an absolute way,
这根本不重要，结果如何。
that doesn't matter at all, how the result looks like.
但是由于我们定位这个伪元素
But since we are positioning this pseudo element
无论如何，以绝对的方式，
in an absolute way, anyway,
它不会改变它的外观，
it doesn't change how it looks like,
无论我们使用之后还是之前。
no matter if we use after or before.
好的。
Nice.
所以有了这个，
So with this,
我们实际上完成了 CSS 基础的这一部分。
we actually finished this part of the CSS fundamentals.
如此出色的工作，做得很好，仍然和我在一起，
So great job, and well done for still being with me here,
即使内容变得有点复杂，
even as the content is getting a little bit more complex,
也许有点难以理解。
and maybe a little bit harder to understand.
但这只是学习之旅的一部分。
But that's just part of the learning journey.
所以只要确保你真的了解一切
And so just make sure that you really understand everything
我在这里通过练习向你展示。
that I show you here by practicing.
并且总是审查每堂课的代码。
And by always reviewing the code for each lecture.
现在接下来的两堂课
Now the next two lectures
将涉及一些开发人员技能
will be about some developer skills
这对你很重要
that are important for you
当您开始您作为 Web 开发人员的旅程时。
as you start your journey as a web developer.
然后在那之后，
And then after that,
我们有一个最后的编码挑战，
we have one final coding challenge for the section,
这样你就可以练习我们刚刚学到的东西
so that you can practice what we just learned
在这最后几个视频中。
over these last couple of videos.
所以接下来的几个视频很重要，
So for the next few videos are very important,
我认为非常令人兴奋。
and very exciting, I think.
所以很快见。
And so see you there soon.